

## **ODINAKACHUKWU EZEOBIKA**

**Software Engineer Graphic / UI Designer** 

### PERSONAL INFO

- 7, Kehinde Aderinokun Close, Ire-Akari Estate, Isolo, Lagos, LA, 100263
- +234703 932 4997
- solomonzbk@gmail.com
- https://github.com/ODINAKACHUKWU

### SKILLS

- **⊿** Ruby
- JavaScript
- **■■** NodeJS

- Ruby on Rails
- ReactJS
- **■** Redux
- Express
- Bootstrap
- **■** JQuery
- Sinatra
- React Native

HTML5, CSS, Sass, REST

**JSON** 

SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQlite, Sequelize ORM, GraphQL



## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hello! I am a software engineer and graphic/UI designer with 2+ years professional experience. I started off my career freelancing as a graphic/UI designer and then evolved into web application developer.

I am passionate about building solutions that improve business efficiency and provide better service to the public. I am driven by the desire to make people's lives easier!

## **WORK HISTORY**

**Software Engineer** 

Jan 2019 - Mar 2020

Andela, Lagos

### **Backend Developer**

Nov 2019 - Feb 2020

Omise Co. Ltd. Bangkok, Thailand (Remote)

Omise is a payment gateway solution with powerful features that enable fast, flexible, and seamless payment experiences helping users maximise business opportunities and accelerate growth. The application was developed using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL while the frontend was developed with ReactJS.

At Omise I worked with a team of developers to help build and maintain Omise API endpoints. I contributed to the team by:

- Building API endpoints
- Fixing bugs, maintaining and refactoring legacy codes
- Writing unit test for all features implemented
- Actively participating in all activities of my team (Core API)

#### **Notable Achievement:**

Before joining Omise, all system admin secrets were stored in one table using a single Secret model. I remodelled and extracted the secrets into separate models shared by common secrets; properly validated the attributes for each secret and defined methods for rich API consumption

#### **Product Owner** Aug 2019 - Sep 2020 **Barefoot Nomad (via Andela Blended Learning Program)**

Barefoot Nomad is an app that enables employees of a company easily and conveniently book their international travel and accommodation globally; across all the locations/centres where the company has its operations. The application was developed with NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, Redux and PostgreSQL.

As a PO, I ensured the development of the right product to satisfy the needs of the users and business of the product.

#### **Full-stack Developer** April - June 2019 VOF (Value alignment, Output quality and Feedback)

VOF is a hub for pre-fellowship learners, bootcamp learning facilitators and program designers. This hub enables peer-to-peer interactions, performance evaluation and pre-fellowship program design respectively. The application was developed using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.

- Built API endpoints
- Fixed bugs and refactored legacy codes
- Wrote unit test for all features implemented
- Built the frontend page for Pitch feature
- Facilitated a coaching session on designing and prototyping UI with

### **Notable Achievement:**

I developed a feature that enables program designers to generate and share a survey link to pre-fellowship leaners.

#### Dev Tools

Git, Visual Studio Code, ESLint

#### Work / Collaboration Tools

GitHub, Slack, Bitbucket, Trello, Pivotal tracker, Jira, Phabricator, Zoom, Jitsi meet

### Testing Tools

Postman, Mocha & Chai, RSpec, Enzyme & Jest, Minitest, Insomnia

### DevOps / Cloud Tools

Circle CI, Travis CI, Coveralls, Heroku, Hound CI, Code Climate

### Design Tools

- Corel Draw
- Adobe Illustrator
- **→** Figma
- Lunacy
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Xd

### Motion Graphic Tools

- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Adobe After Effects

#### Others

- Google Suite
- Microsoft Office Suite

## PERSONAL TRAITS

- Great communication skill
- Good interpersonal skill
- Highly analytical
- Personal initiative
- Leadership

## Full-stack Developer

**Authors Haven** 

Authors Haven is a social web application platform where like-minded authors foster inspirations and innovations through creative writing.

#### Role:

On this project, I worked with a team of 6 engineers using **NodeJS**, **Express**, **ReactJS**, **Redux**, **PostgreSQL** and **Sequelize ORM**.

I contributed to this project by:

- Designing and prototyping the UI pages using Figma.
- Building API endpoints
- Building UI components for the frontend application
- Writing unit tests for all features implemented

#### Freelance Graphic & UI Designer

July 2017 - Dec 2018

#### Role:

- Conceptualised and created graphic designs and illustrations for marketing materials and ads utilising Corel draw, Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop
- Developed business collaterals including logo, branding, brochures, posters, flyers, business cards, web assets, etc for use by SMEs
- Offered print solutions to a variety of businesses such as DI, cord, 201, etc.
- Developed and implemented designs for existing and new product packaging as well as book covers
- Collaborated with various clients as a freelance designer to produce detailed visuals and illustrations while creating designs specific to client requests and desires

# **EDUCATION**

## B.Eng. in Civil/Structural Engineering

2014

2016

Federal University of Technology, Owerri



## **Project Management Professional**

Project Management Professional Institute, Nigeria



- Backend
- Frontend
- Fullstack
- Graphic / UI Designer

# $\bigcirc$

## **NON-WORK INTERESTS**

When I am not coding, I listen to music, sing or play my favourite musical instrument - the keyboard. I love to research, and travel so as to learn new things, gain new experiences, see new places, meet new people, try new foods, make memories that will last a lifetime.

Jan - April 2019